<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks on Natalie Chin</title>
    <link>natchineth.com/talks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Talks on Natalie Chin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="natchineth.com/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking Imposter Syndrome</title>
      <link>natchineth.com/talk/hacking-imposter-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>natchineth.com/talk/hacking-imposter-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;70% of people have experienced some form of imposter syndrome at least once in their lives. It is this nagging feeling that we think someone else might find out that we&amp;rsquo;re a &amp;lsquo;fake&amp;rsquo; - that our achievements are solely due to luck, and nothing to do with skill, talent, or our effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, in recent years, people have started to become more vocal about experiencing Imposter Syndrome - but I think there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more to be done. Being vocal is only the start. We need to start sharing experiences and strategies to deal with it. Otherwise, it&amp;rsquo;s not going to get better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I want to share my experiences and my strategies - or hacks that I used to deal with it. I hope to share it so you can use them or find out what works for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/Women-Who-Code-Toronto/events/265312120/&#34;&gt;Sign up here if you are interested!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Smart Contracts</title>
      <link>natchineth.com/talks/introduction-to-smart-contracts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>natchineth.com/talks/introduction-to-smart-contracts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tune into www.womenwhocode.com/blockchain to sign up for the webinar!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kickass Blockchain Developer Journeys</title>
      <link>natchineth.com/talks/kickass-blockchain-developer-journeys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>natchineth.com/talks/kickass-blockchain-developer-journeys/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join me and a few other professors at George Brown discussing our journeys of how we got into blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Solidity</title>
      <link>natchineth.com/talks/introduction-to-solidity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 09:22:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>natchineth.com/talks/introduction-to-solidity/</guid>
      <description>Happy International Women’s Day! Excited to end the day with an Introduction to Solidity talk at ETH U of T from 8-9pm!
The significance of this day has brought me to reflect on the progression of the past year. Days before starting my first coop, I remember admitting to Alic how I thought my skills were inadequate to be a blockchain developer. He told me to trust myself, and that I’m smarter than I think I am.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Blockchain</title>
      <link>natchineth.com/talks/introduction-to-blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 09:23:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>natchineth.com/talks/introduction-to-blockchain/</guid>
      <description>After a few years of organizing McMaster&amp;rsquo;s annual DeltaHacks, super happy to be back as a speaker and mentor this coming weekend. I&amp;rsquo;ll be going into a Deep Dive of Blockchain, discussing how it works, its business use case, how to set up development environments, and live coding examples. I&amp;rsquo;m also epically excited to see the team again! Keep going guys - it&amp;rsquo;s the last stretch! 🎉
Who: 👋 🙃</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>